Pedro Souza

Full Stack Web Developer

Profile

Recent coding bootcamp graduate at *Le Wagon*. Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer with considerable experience in technology. I can deliver *Front-End* and *Back-End* projects with with payment integration, admin interface, user management, mailer, geolocation and many other features.

Objective

I'm looking to work as a Full Stack Developer at a company where I can develop my Front-End and Back-End skills so we can both grow together.

Web Development Summary

- Algorithms and Programming with Ruby.
- Web Application Development with Ruby on Rails.
- Web Application Diagram (MVC, user stories, database schema).
- SQL, mySQL and PostgreSQL Database
- Front-End Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript (jQuery) + Boostrap
- Collaborative coding with Git and Github
- Deployment on Heroku
- o Team project: built a finance platform for SMEs to pre-finance their open invoices in 10 days: www.advalori.com
 Technical environment: Ruby, ruby on rails, Postgres, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Git / Github, gem (devise, activeadmin, pundit, rails admin, stripe, geocoder...)

Work Experience

2014-2016 Linux System Admin, Equinix Data Centers, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.

Setup, manage, and maintain various Linux based IT servers (hardware, operating systems), Virtual servers, Storage sub-systems, Monitoring and Backup Infrastructure. Support issues like network TCP/IP, Internet application, Firewall, LoadBalance, WebProxy and network security.

2010-2013 Network Support Engineer, 012 Global Inc., Boca Raton FL, USA.

Responsible for support of SIP, RTP, UDP and TCP/IP protocols using Linux and Wireshark. Troubleshoot and isolate network issues and coordinate problem resolution. Responsible to install, configure and troubleshoot network, hardware and software issues for in house team members.

2007-2010 Client Support Services, Citigrooup, Tampa FL, USA.

Responsible for the daily processing and support of Brazilian and Mexican/Latam Settlements for Citigroup global client base. Provided software and front end support to all Citi's global client base.

2003-2006 **Network Technical Support**, *Dendrite International*, Bedminster NJ, USA.

Provided effective and consistent technical phone support for Pharmaceutical Companies like, Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Fujisawa and others. Responsible for site setup activities to first time users including connectivity, hardware and software.

Education

2017-Present **Western Governors University**, *B.S. Software Development*, Salt Lake City,UT USA, . Currently enrolled as a part-time student.

2003-2004 **The Chubb Institute**, *Network Systems Technician*, Parsippany,NJ USA, . Graduated with Honors/ GPA: 4.0

Languages

Fluent in English, Portuguese and communicate effectively in Spanish.